spreadshirt.com 2019-12-26

# Privacy Policy | Spreadshirt

Thank you for your interest in our website. In the following, we will inform you in detail about the processing of personal data when using this website. Personal data means all data that can be personally related to you, e.g. name, address, telephone number, email address or user behavior.

## 1\. Who is responsible for data processing?

The service provider and party responsible for processing personal data (“controller”) is Spreadshirt, Inc., 1572 Roseytown Road, Greensburg, PA 15601 (“Spreadshirt”).

If you have any questions about the collection, processing, or usage of data; if you have requests for information, correction, disabling or deletion of data; or if you want to revoke a previously given consent; or if you want to object to the usage of your information for advertising purposes, please use the settings provided in your account’s user area, or else contact us at one of the following addresses:

Email: [info@spreadshirt.com](mailto:info@spreadshirt.com)  
Fax: 1-877-202-0251  
Postal Mail: 1572 Roseytown Road, Greensburg, PA 15601 

## 2\. To what extent is personal data processed?

## 2.1 Collection of personal data when you visit our website

### a) Log files

If you visit our site for informational purposes but don’t register with us, create an account, order something, or otherwise deliberately transfer information to us, we collect information from your browser to help us serve our websites to you. In particular, we collect 

  * IP address,
  * date and time of the request,
  * time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT),
  * name of the requested file,
  * access status/HTTP status code,
  * volume of data transferred,
  * the page from which you came to visit us,
  * your operating system and its interface,
  * your browser type and the language and version of the browser software,
  * a report of successful retrieval

The data is technically necessary for us to display our website to you. It is also evaluated to make the website user-friendly and to ensure stability and security. For this purpose, we partly use the external web hosting service providers Akamai Technologies, Inc. and Amazon Web Services, Inc.

### b) Cookies and similar technologies

We also use “cookies” on our sites. Cookies are small text files that are assigned to your browser and stored on your device. Through them, certain information flows to the place that sets the cookie, such as settings or data for exchange with the system. This helps us to make our website more user-friendly and effective overall. The legal bases for this are your consent and our legitimate interests. Cookies cannot execute programs or transmit viruses to your device. 

We use session cookies, persistent cookies, and third-party cookies.

Session cookies store what’s called a session ID, which can be used to assign different requests of your browser to a common session. This allows your device to be recognized when you return to our website. For example, this lets you store certain information you have entered (such as log-in information, language settings) in such a way that you do not have to repeat it constantly. Session cookies are automatically deleted when you log out or close your browser.

Persistent cookies remain on your device for the time being, so that we can recognize your browser on your next visit and we can, for example, assign your preferred information and settings. Long-term cookies are automatically deleted after a specified period, which may vary depending on the cookie.

When you visit our website, our partner companies also store third-party cookies on your device. The cookies contain information about how our website is used, e.g. which pages and products were visited. The data is collected in a pseudonymized form by assigning an identification number, which is not combined with any other personal data you may have provided to us.

You can delete cookies in your browser settings at any time or prevent them from being stored, although the latter may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. In the relevant sections of this Privacy Policy, we explain which technologies that are comparable to cookies are used on our website and how you can object to the use of cookies and other technologies with the individual third-party providers.

## 2.2 Ordering from Spreadshirt / User Account

a) If you want to order something in our online shop, it is necessary for the conclusion of the contract that you give us the personal data we need to process the order. The mandatory data required to process the contract is marked as such; all other data you provide is voluntary. You can either enter your data only once for the order or use your email address to set up a password-protected user account with us, in which your data can be stored for later purchases until you revoke your consent. You can deactivate or delete the data and the user account at any time via the account.

To prevent unauthorized access to your personal data by third parties, the order process is encrypted using TLS technology.

When we process the data provided by you to process your order, this includes, for example, individual customer service. In the course of order processing, we pass on personal data to one of our production companies within the group, to a shipping company commissioned by us and (with the exception of PayPal) to our bank, ADYEN B.V., Simon Carmiggeltstraat 6-50, 1011 DJ Amsterdam, Netherlands (“Adyen”). The payment data is encrypted and transmitted directly to Adyen.

Payment via PayPal is processed by PayPal, 2211 North First Street San Jose, California 95131 (“PayPal”). For information about data protection at PayPal, please refer to PayPal’s privacy policy: <https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>.

In the case of trackable parcels, we also pass on your order and address data to various service providers, depending on your delivery choices, shipping rates, and your chosen delivery destination.

The legal bases for the processing of personal data as part of order processing are to perform under a contract and our legitimate interests. Due to commercial and tax regulations, we are obliged to store your order, address and payment data for a period of ten years.

b) During the order process we also conduct a fraud prevention check via our bank Adyen, which involves using your IP address to carry out a geolocalization and compare your data with previous experience. This may mean that an order cannot be placed with the selected payment method. Our aim in this regard is to prevent any abuse of your chosen payment method by third parties and to protect ourselves from payment defaults. The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interests.

Since this involves automated decision-making, you have the right to challenge the decision (in this case the refusal of a certain payment method) and have the decision reviewed by a person. In such cases we ask that you contact us using the contact details mentioned in Section 1. Please note that the payment method may have been rejected due to a typing error and you should, therefore, check what you have entered again during the order process if necessary.

c) During the ordering process we use Google Maps Autocomplete, a service of Google LLC (“Google”). This allows an address you start typing to be completed automatically, avoiding delivery errors. Google sometimes conducts a geolocalization using your IP address and receives the information that you have retrieved the corresponding subpage of our website. In addition, the data referred to in Section 2.1 is transmitted. This is regardless of whether you have a Google account and are logged in. Once you are logged in to your Google Account, the information will be directly associated with your account. If you do not want this assignment to occur, you must log out before entering your address. Google stores your data as user profiles and uses it (even in the case of users who are not logged in) for the purposes of advertising, market research and/or the needs-oriented design of its own website. You can object to Google creating such user profiles. For more information about the purpose and scope of data processing by Google and about protecting your privacy, please refer to Google’s Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. The binding terms of use for Google Maps/Google Earth can be found here: <https://www.google.com/help/terms_maps.html>. Third-party provider information: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interests.

d) After you place an order, we will process your order and address data to send you a personalized email asking you to rate our products. By obtaining ratings, our aim is to improve our services and adapt them to our customers’ wishes. We use the feedback software of eKomi Ltd, Markgrafenstraße 11, 10969 Berlin, Germany (“eKomi”). For the purpose of sending the feedback email (and in the event that a moderation or conciliation procedure is conducted via eKomi following negative feedback), we pass on your email address, name, order number, product types and a unique ID to eKomi for identification purposes and in order to generate a feedback link.

The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interests. If you no longer want your data to be used for this purpose, you can object to this at any time. Just click on the unsubscribe link included with each email or send a message using the contact details provided under Section 1.

e) We also use Google Customer Reviews, a service of Google Ireland Ltd. (“Google”), through which we receive feedback about us as a seller and about our products. This allows us to improve our services and adapt them to our customers’ wishes. The legal basis is our legitimate interests. After placing an order, you can give Google permission to use your email address to request a review. You can revoke your consent to the use of your data at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link contained in the emails from Google. For more detailed information about the purpose and scope of data processing by Google and about protecting your privacy, please refer to Google’s Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. Third-party provider information: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

## 2.3 Spreadshirt Partners: Shop Partners and Marketplace Designers

a) If you want to offer designs on our marketplace or operate a shop, it is necessary for the conclusion of a contract with us that you use your email address to open a password-protected user account and store your name and address there. For the payout of earnings, it is necessary that you additionally provide your bank details or your PayPal information as well as information about your tax status. Any other information you may provide to us when using the account is voluntary. You do not have to enter a real name when choosing your username. You can manage and change this information in your account. You can also deactivate or erase it – or the entire user account. If this affects data necessary for the performance of the contract, we may retain that data for a longer period in accordance with commercial and tax regulations (standard period of ten years). We process this data to conduct the contractual relationship that exists with you; the legal bases are to perform under a contract and our legitimate interests. 

b) Within the scope of the contractual relationship, we also process the email address provided by you in order to send you emails at irregular intervals containing information and tips about the Marketplace and your shops (“Partner Newsletter”). We use your name to allow us to personalize these emails. To this end, the data is passed on to the software company Emarsys eMarketing Systems AG, Hans-Fischer-Straße 10, 80339 Munich, Germany (“Emarsys”), which handles the technical side of the mailing on our behalf. You can unsubscribe from the Partner Newsletter at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided in each email, informing us via the contact details specified in Section 1, or changing your newsletter settings in your user account (“Account Settings” – “Newsletter subscriptions”).

When sending the Partner Newsletter, we use Emarsys to statistically evaluate your user behavior in order to optimize the design. To enable this evaluation, the emails contain what are called web beacons or tracking pixels. These are single-pixel image files that establish a connection to our website und thus permit a log file analysis. The web beacons are linked with the data mentioned in Section 2.1 a and an individual ID. The links contained in the email also contain this ID. For example, we can see if and when an email has been opened and which links have been clicked on. The data is stored on the Emarsys servers for 13 months and collected pseudonymously, meaning the IDs are not linked to other personal data at this point, thus ruling out any possibility of direct personal reference. You can object to the recording of your usage behavior at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided in each email, informing us via the contact options listed in Section 1, or changing the newsletter settings in your user account (“Account settings” – “Newsletter subscriptions”). Recording is not possible if you have disabled the display of images in your email settings. In this case, the newsletter will not be displayed to you in full and you may not be able to use all functions. If you choose to display the images manually, recording will take place as described above.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent, to perform under a contract, and our legitimate interests.

c) If you store your address in your user account, we use Google Maps Autocomplete, a service of Google LLC (“Google”). This allows an address you start typing to be completed automatically. This helps us verify your address, which we do for tax reasons. Google sometimes conducts a geolocalization using your IP address. We also use Google Fonts to enhance the user experience in the Partner section of your account as well as Google Calendar to inform you about Partner-related promotions for customers. Via these services and applications, Google receives the information that you have retrieved the corresponding subpage of our website. In addition, the data referred to in Section 2.1 is transmitted. This is regardless of whether you have a Google account and are logged in. Once you are logged in to your Google Account, the information will be directly associated with your account. If you do not want this assignment to occur, you must log out before entering your address. Google stores your data as user profiles and uses it (even in the case of users who are not logged in) for the purposes of advertising, market research and/or the needs-oriented design of its own website. You can object to Google creating such user profiles. For more detailed information about the purpose and scope of data processing by Google and about protecting your privacy, please refer to Google’s Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. The binding terms of use for Google Maps/Google Earth can be found here: <https://www.google.com/help/terms_maps.html>. Third-party provider information: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interests.

## 2.4 Communication with Spreadshirt

### a) Establishing contact

If you contact us via a contact form, letter, fax, email, social media or telephone, we process the data provided by you for the purpose of processing your inquiry and for advertising purposes. We use the software of Sematell GmbH, Neugrabenweg 1, 66123 Saarbrücken, Germany, to coordinate and process emails, which means that Sematell GmbH gains access to the data. We use the management software of Hootsuite Media, Inc, 5 East 8th Avenue, Vancouver, BC, Canada to coordinate and process enquiries via our social media channels Twitter, Facebook and Instagram. The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interests. If the aim of establishing contact is to conclude a contract, then an additional legal basis is to perform under a contract.

### b) Blog

In our blog, where we publish various articles on topics related to our activities, you can post public comments. Your comment will be published along with your chosen username. We recommend using a pseudonym instead of your real name. It is necessary to provide a username and email address, while all other information is voluntary. The necessary information is processed to run the blog. We need your email address to contact you if a third party should complain that your comment is unlawful. We reserve the right to delete comments if third parties complain that they are unlawful. The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interests.

### c) Forum

With the exception of a few sections, our Forum can be read without the need to register. If you wish to actively participate in the Forum under your chosen username, you must log in using your Spreadshirt user account access data. To open a Spreadshirt user account, only your email address and a password are required. We process your activities (public posts, private messages, likes, profile information, activity logs) and your IP address in order to operate the Forum. The legal basis is our legitimate interests. If you deactivate or delete your user account, your public posts will continue to be visible. If you would like your public posts to be deleted, please contact us using the contact details provided in Section 1. When writing a comment and in the Forum settings (under “Preferences” – “Emails” and “Notifications”), you can specify in which cases and to what extent you would like to be notified by email about new activities in the Forum. You can unsubscribe again at any time, either in the Forum settings or by clicking on the unsubscribe link contained in the respective notification email.

### d) LiveChat

We also use LiveChat Inc.’s services on our forum to enable our customer service team to interact with you live through our website and provide you with real-time assistance. Livechat collects and processes information in order to enable Spreadshirt to provide you with customer service. LiveChat may collect device information such as device type, operating system type and application version to provide an optimized version of their applications for your device type. LiveChat also collects and processes your data related to your use of their customer support software and services. LiveChat uses such data for statistics purposes, to improve their services, or to create and improve new services. LiveChat collects and processes such data collectively and anonymously. LiveChat uses cookies to personalize its services to Spreadshirt and to you, but does not collect personal information with these cookies and does not link the cookie information with personal information that LiveChat may otherwise possess. LiveChat also collects your name, email address, and other information that you provide through its service and shares this with Spreadshirt in order to provide you with customer service.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: LiveChat, Inc., One International Place Suite 1400 Boston, MA 02110-2619 USA. LiveChat Privacy policy: <https://www.livechatinc.com/privacy-policy/>.

## 2.5 Processing of data for web analytics

### a) Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Ireland Ltd. (“Google”). Google uses cookies (see Section 2.1 b), which enable an analysis of your use of our website. The information generated by the cookie about usage is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, due to the activation of IP anonymization on our website, where applicable, your IP address will first be shortened by Google within the Member States of the European Union or in other states party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On our behalf, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide us with other services relating to website and internet use.

The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics will not be combined with other data held by Google.

You can prevent the storage of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser software; however, please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website. You can also prevent the data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) from being recorded and processed by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>. Specifically in the case of mobile devices, you can prevent Google Analytics from recording data by clicking here: DisableEnable Google Analytics. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website.

This website uses Google Analytics with the “_anonymizeIp()” extension. Consequently, IP addresses are further processed in shortened form, so that any personal association with the data subject can be ruled out. As far as the data collected about you relates to you personally, that association is therefore ruled out immediately and the personal data thus erased without delay.

We use Google Analytics to analyze and regularly improve the use of our website. The statistics this yields allow us to improve our website and make it more interesting for you as a user. The legal bases for our use of Google Analytics are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. See also the terms of use (<https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>) and privacy overview ([https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245? ](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?)) for Google Analytics as well as Google’s privacy policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.

### b) Adobe Analytics

To allow us to analyze and regularly improve the use of our website, our website also uses the Adobe Analytics web analytics service. The statistics this yields allow us to improve our website and make it more interesting for you as a user. The legal bases for our use of Adobe Analytics are your consent and our legitimate interests.

The analysis involves storing cookies (see Section 2.1 b) on your device. The information collected in this way is stored on servers, including in the USA. We would like to point out that if you prevent the storage of cookies, you may not be able to use this website in its entirety. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies. You can also prevent Adobe Analytics from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable Adobe Analytics. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. How to prevent the recording of your data on other websites is explained on the respective sites and at [https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html](https://www.adobe.com/%20privacy/opt-out.html).

Our website uses Adobe Analytics with the settings “Before Geo-Lookup: Replace visitor’s last IP octet with 0” and “Obfuscate IP-Removed”, which removes the last octet from your IP address and replaces it with a generic IP address, i.e. one that can no longer be assigned. Any personal connection can therefore be ruled out.

Third-party provider information: Adobe Systems Incorporated, 345 Park Avenue, San Jose, CA 95110-2704, privacy@adobe.com; Adobe’s privacy policy: [https://www.adobe.com/privacy/policy.html ](https://www.adobe.com/%20privacy/policy.html).

### c) Adobe Target

Our website also uses the Adobe Target analytics service. With the help of this service we can carry out so-called A/B tests on the website. The software renders to a certain user group a version of the website that is different from the original version (e.g. with a different design or different content). This makes it possible to analyze and compare user behavior on both versions and optimize the website. The legal bases for our use of Adobe Target are your consent and our legitimate interests.

The information generated using cookies (see Section 2.1 b) is stored on servers, including in the USA. Our website uses Adobe Target with the settings “Before Geo-Lookup: Replace visitor’s last IP octet with 0” and “Obfuscate IP-Removed”, which removes the last octet from your IP address and replaces it with a generic IP address, i.e. one that can no longer be assigned. Any personal connection can therefore be ruled out.

You can prevent cookies from being saved in your browser settings. Please note that in this case you may not be able to use the website in its entirety. You can also prevent Adobe Analytics and thus Adobe Target from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable Adobe Analytics. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. How to prevent the recording of your data on other websites is explained on the respective sites and at https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html.

### d) SessionCam

Our website also uses the analytics service of SessionCam Ltd.(“SessionCam”). Cookies (see Section 2.1 b) are used to record and analyze your mouse movements, click behavior, scrolling and text input on the website. Personal data such as your name or bank data is masked during recording. IP addresses are pseudonymized and not linked to the respective recording. The information generated by the cookie is transferred to a SessionCam server and stored there. The data collected by SessionCam is for our internal analysis only. It is used to improve the user experience on our website. The legal bases for this are your consent and our legitimate interests.

You can adjust your browser settings to prevent cookies from being saved. Please note that by doing this you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website. You can also prevent SessionCam from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable SessionCam. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. How to prevent the recording of your data on other websites is explained on the respective sites and at [https://sessioncam.com/choose-not-to-be-recorded/](https://sessioncam.com/opt-out-of-sessioncam-recording/).

Third-party provider information: SessionCam Ltd., St. Vedast House, St. Vedast Street, Norwich NR1 1BT, England. For detailed information on privacy at SessionCam, please refer to SessionCam’s privacy policy: <https://sessioncam.com/privacy-policy-cookies/>.

### e) Web analytics by Spreadshirt’s Shop Partners

Our partners can also use the Google Analytics web analytics service (see Section 2.5 a) in their Spreadshirt shops themselves, as a rule to analyze use of the shop and improve their offer in the shop. In this case, they determine the purposes and means of processing personal data. The name and contact details of our partners are stored in the legal information section of the respective shop.

## 2.6 Advertising activities by Spreadshirt

### a) Newsletter

If you register separately for our newsletter via our website and give us your consent, we will use your email address to send you regular emails about product offers, discounts and contests. To this end, we pass the data on to the software company Emarsys eMarketing Systems AG, Hans-Fischer-Straße 10, 80339 Munich, Germany (“Emarsys”), which handles the technical side of the mailing on our behalf.

When you register for our newsletter, we use the so-called double opt-in procedure. This means that after you register we will send you an email to the email address you provided, in which we ask you to confirm that you would like to receive the newsletter. If you do not confirm your registration, your information will be automatically deleted after one month. On the other hand, if you confirm the newsletter subscription, we will save your email address for the purpose of sending you the newsletter until you unsubscribe from the newsletter.

 **You can revoke your consent to the sending of the newsletter at any time (without this affecting the lawfulness of the processing up to the point of revocation). You can declare your revocation by clicking on the link provided in every newsletter email, by emailing[info@spreadshirt.com](mailto:info@spreadshirt.com) or by sending a message to the contact details provided in Section 1.**

When sending the newsletter, we use Emarsys to statistically evaluate your user behavior in order to measure how successful the newsletter is and to optimize its design. To enable this evaluation, the emails contain what are called web beacons or tracking pixels. These are single-pixel image files that establish a connection to our website und thus permit a log file analysis. The web beacons are linked with the data mentioned in Section 2.1 a and an individual ID. The links contained in the newsletter also contain this ID. For example, we can see if and when an email has been opened and which links have been clicked on. The data is stored on the Emarsys servers for 13 months and collected pseudonymously, meaning the IDs are not linked to other personal data at this point, thus ruling out any possibility of direct personal reference. You can object to the recording of your usage behavior at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided in each email or by informing us using the contact details provided in Section 1. Recording is not possible if you have disabled the display of images in your email settings. In this case, the newsletter will not be displayed to you in full and you may not be able to use all functions. If you choose to display the images manually, recording will take place as described above.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

### b) Product recommendations

As a Spreadshirt customer, i.e., if you order something in our online shop (see Section 2.2 a), we process the email address you provide in order to send you regular email recommendations for products that might be of interest to you based on your previous orders from us. We also use your name to allow us to personalize these emails. The data is passed on to the software company Emarsys (see Section 2.6 a), which handles the technical side of the mailing on our behalf. The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interests. 

You receive these product recommendations because you did not object to the use of your email address for this purpose by removing the corresponding check mark during the order process. If you subsequently no longer wish to receive product recommendations or any advertising messages, you can object at any time without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs at the basic rates. Just click on the unsubscribe link included with each email, send a message using the contact details provided under Section 1 or – if you have a user account with us – adjust your newsletter settings accordingly (“Account settings” - “Newsletter subscriptions”).

When sending the product recommendations, we use Emarsys to statistically evaluate your user behavior in order to measure their success and to optimize their design. The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests. To enable this evaluation, the emails contain what are called web beacons or tracking pixels. These are single-pixel image files that establish a connection to our website und thus permit a log file analysis. The web beacons are linked with the data mentioned in Section 2.1 a and an individual ID. The links contained in the email also contain this ID. For example, we can see if and when an email has been opened and which links have been clicked on. The data is stored on the Emarsys servers for 13 months and collected pseudonymously, meaning the IDs are not linked to other personal data at this point, thus ruling out any possibility of direct personal reference. You can object to the recording of your usage behavior at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided in each email, informing us via the contact options listed in Section 1, or – if you have a user account with us – changing the newsletter settings in your user account (“Account settings” – “Newsletter subscriptions”). Recording is not possible if you have disabled the display of images in your email settings. In this case, the newsletter will not be displayed to you in full and you may not be able to use all functions. If you choose to display the images manually, recording will take place as described above.

### c) Newsletters and product recommendations from Spreadshirt Shop Partners

In exceptional cases where you register separately in a Spreadshirt shop for a Shop Partner’s newsletter and thus give your consent, we transmit your email address to the Shop Partner so that it can send you emails on product offers, discounts and contests.

 **You can revoke your consent to the sending of the newsletter at any time (without this affecting the lawfulness of the processing up to the point of revocation). This revocation must be declared vis-à-vis the Shop Partner. The contact details of the respective Shop Partner can be found in the legal information section of their Spreadshirt shop.**

The legal basis for the processing is your consent.

### d) Text Message Promotions

Our website uses Attentive Mobile, Inc.’s services in order to offer special promotions via text message. This service allows you to click a promotional link which pre-populates a text message on your web-enabled mobile device. Sending this message acts as affirmative consent, or an opt-in, to receive the applicable advertised promotion as well as later promotions which are sent via text message to the same number that sent the opt-in. There are no additional fees associated with this feature; your ordinary mobile text messaging rates will apply to all messages sent and received in connection with these promotions.

Your phone number and any other information you submit via text message through the Attentive text message promotional system will be shared with Attentive in order to enable Attentive to provide this service to us. Attentive may also receive standard technical information when you interact with the Attentive service, including browser and device information such as unique device identifiers, internet protocol (IP) addresses (which may identify your general geographic location), browser types, and the date and time. Attentive also receives information about your interactions with Attentive’s service and Spreadshirt’s websites that incorporate the Attentive service, such as which pages you visited and how much time was spent on the page. Some of this information is collected using cookies (see Section 2.1 b for more information about cookies). Attentive uses this information to provide the service to Spreadshirt and you and to monitor, evaluate, and improve its service. Spreadshirt may combine this information with other information it already collects about your use of Spreadshirt’s website in order to provide advertising that is more interesting to you.

 **You can revoke your consent to the sending of these text message promotions at any time (without this affecting the lawfulness of the processing and messaging up to the point of revocation). To revoke your consent and unsubscribe, send a message containing any one (but only one) of the following words to the same number that sends the promotional messages: STOP, END, CANCEL, UNSUBSCRIBE, or QUIT.** You may also send only the word “HELP” to the same number that sends the promotional messages for more instructions on how to interact with the promotional text messaging service. If you have any questions or problems (especially with unsubscribing from messages), you can contact us at [info@spreadshirt.com](mailto:info@spreadshirt.com).

The legal basis for the processing is your consent.

Third-party provider information: Attentive Mobile, Inc., 56 Fifth Avenue, Suite 303 New York, NY 10010. Attentive privacy policy: <https://attentivemobile.com/privacy/>.

## 2.7 Usage-based online advertising

Our website uses various conversion tracking and retargeting technologies made available by other service providers. We use these technologies to make our website interesting for you. The information also helps us to address users who have already shown an interest in our products with individually tailored advertising on the websites of our partner companies. We assume that the display of personalized, interest-based advertising is generally more interesting for the internet user than advertising that has no such personal relevance. At the same time, we want to avoid inappropriate and intrusive advertising.

General information about third-party advertising-based technologies and how to disable them can be found on the following websites, among others:

  * Your Online Choices: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>
  * YourAdChoices: <http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>
  * Network Advertising Initiative: <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>

### a) Use of Google AdWords conversion tracking and Google AdWords remarketing

We use Google AdWords, a service of Google LLC (“Google”), to use ads (so-called Google AdWords) to draw attention to our offers on external websites. In relation to the data of advertising campaigns, we can identify how successful the individual advertising activities are. In this way we want to show you advertising that is of interest to you, make our website more attractive to you and achieve a fair calculation of advertising costs.

These ads are deployed by Google via ‘ad servers’. For this purpose, we use ad server cookies, which enable the tracking of certain parameters for measuring success, such as the display of ads or clicks by users. If you arrive at our website via a Google ad, Google AdWords will store a cookie on your device. These cookies usually expire after 30 days and are not intended to identify you personally. Analysis values usually stored for this cookie are the unique cookie ID, the number of ad impressions per placement (frequency), the last impression (relevant for post-view conversions) and opt-out information (marker showing that the user no longer wishes to be targeted).

These cookies allow Google to recognize your internet browser. If a user visits certain pages of an AdWords customer’s website (in this case ours) and the cookie stored on their device has not yet expired, Google and the customer can recognize that the user has clicked on the ad and has been redirected to this site. Each AdWords customer is assigned a different cookie. Cookies cannot therefore be tracked via the websites of AdWords customers. We do not collect and process any personal data in the aforementioned advertising activities. Google merely provides us with statistical evaluations. On the basis of these evaluations we can identify which of the advertising activities used are particularly effective. We do not receive any further data from the use of ads; in particular we cannot identify users on the basis of this information.

Due to the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection to the Google server. We have no influence on the extent and further processing of the data collected by Google through the use of this tool and therefore inform you according to what we know: By integrating AdWords Conversion, Google receives the information that you have retrieved the corresponding part of our website, or that you have clicked on one of our ads. If you are registered with a Google service, Google can associate the visit with your account. Even if you are not registered with Google or have not logged in, it is possible that Google will obtain and store your IP address.

\- Google AdWords remarketing

Besides AdWords Conversion, we also use Google’s remarketing feature. This is a process we use in an attempt to contact you again. After visiting our website, this feature makes it possible to show you our ads when you continue to use the internet. This is done by means of cookies stored in your browser, which Google uses to record and evaluate your usage behavior when visiting various websites. This is how Google can determine that you have previously visited our website. According to its own information, Google does not combine the data collected in the context of remarketing with your personal data, which may be processed by Google. Specifically, according to Google, pseudonymization is used during remarketing.

There are various ways in which you can prevent your participation in this tracking procedure:

  * By setting your browser software accordingly; in particular, disabling cookies from third party providers means that you will not receive any ads from third-party providers;
  * By permanent deactivation in your browser Firefox, Internet Explorer or Google Chrome via the link: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996?hl=en>. Please note that by doing this you may not be able to properly use the full functionality of our website.
  * By clicking on the following button: DisableEnable Google AdWords. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website.
  * By disabling interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative via the link <http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>; please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies.

The legal bases for the processing of your data are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. For further information about privacy at Google, please refer to: <https://policies.google.com/privacy> and <https://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html>. Alternatively, you can visit the website of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) at: [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

### b) Use of Facebook Custom Audiences, Facebook Website Custom Audiences and Facebook Conversion Tracking

\- Facebook Custom Audiences

Our website also uses the Website Custom Audiences remarketing function of Facebook, Inc. (“Facebook”). This allows users of the website to see interest-based ads (“Facebook Ads”) when visiting the social network Facebook or other websites that also use the process. Our intention here is to show you ads that are of interest to you.

Due to the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection to the Facebook server. We have no influence on the extent and further processing of the data collected by Facebook through the use of this tool and therefore inform you according to what we know: By integrating Facebook Custom Audiences, Facebook receives the information that you have retrieved the corresponding part of our website, or that you have clicked on one of our ads. If you are registered with a Facebook service, Facebook can associate the visit with your account. Even if you are not registered with Facebook or have not logged in, it is possible that Facebook will obtain and store your IP address and other identifying information.

\- Facebook Website Custom Audiences

Our website also uses the Facebook product “Custom Audiences from your website”. For this purpose, we have integrated remarketing tags (so-called Facebook Pixel or web beacon) into our website. The Facebook Pixel is a small piece of JavaScript code that provides a range of functionalities for sending application-specific events and user-defined data to Facebook. We use the Facebook Pixel to track how visitors use our site. The Facebook Pixel records and reports to Facebook information about the user’s browser session, a hashed version of the Facebook ID, and the URL being viewed. Every Facebook user therefore has a device-independent Facebook ID, which enables us to recognize users across multiple devices on the social network Facebook so that we can use Facebook Ads to reach our visitors again for advertising purposes. After 180 days, the user information is deleted until the user returns to our website. No personal information is transmitted to us about individual website visitors, and we can only specifically deploy ads to website custom audiences if the custom audience has reached a critical size. This makes it impossible for us to determine the individual identities of visitors.

\- Facebook Conversion Tracking

We also use the Facebook Pixel on our website to measure the reach of ads. This allows us to track users’ actions after they have seen or clicked on a Facebook Ad. The Facebook Pixel records and reports to Facebook information about the user’s browser session, a hashed version of the Facebook ID, and the URL being viewed. The way it works is comparable to Facebook Website Custom Audiences via the Facebook Pixel, which is already described above. Using the hashed Facebook ID, we can measure the reach and effectiveness of an ad to find out whether you are actually interested in our advertising. This enables us to measure the effectiveness of Facebook Ads for statistical and market research purposes. For us, the data used is not personally identifiable.

You can prevent Facebook from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable Facebook Custom Audiences, Facebook Website Custom Audiences and Facebook Conversion Tracking. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. How to prevent the recording of your data on other websites is explained on the respective sites, and if you are a user who has logged in to Facebook, here: <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_>.

The legal bases for the processing of data when using the functions specified above are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: Facebook, Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA. For more information about data processing by Facebook, please refer to Facebook’s privacy policy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>.

### c) Use of LinkedIn conversion tracking and retargeting

\- LinkedIn conversion tracking

Our website uses the feature “LinkedIn conversion tracking” from LinkedIn Corporation (“LinkedIn”) to measure the reach of ads. This is to determine how successful individual advertising activities are on LinkedIn. Our intention here is to develop and display advertising that is of interest to you and make our website more attractive. For this purpose, the LinkedIn Insight Tag is integrated into our website. This JavaScript code enables LinkedIn to use cookies to collect pseudonymous data about your visit and the use of our website (e.g. about the browser session and the website displayed) and to provide us with aggregated, non-personal statistics on this basis. This allows us to trace the actions that have taken place after a LinkedIn ad has been viewed or clicked on.

\- LinkedIn website retargeting

Our website also uses the “LinkedIn website retargeting” feature. After visiting our website, this feature makes it possible to show you our ads when you continue to use the internet. Our intention here is to show you ads that are of interest to you. This is done by means of a cookie stored in your browser (see above for more information), which is used to record and evaluate your usage behavior. No personal information is transmitted to us about individual website visitors, and we can only specifically deploy ads to website custom audiences if the custom audience has reached a critical size. This makes it impossible for us to determine the individual identities of visitors.

There are various ways in which you can disable this tracking. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies, although this may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. You also can prevent LinkedIn from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable LinkedIn conversion tracking and website retargeting. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. In addition, you can disable interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>) or e.g. part of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>); please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies.

he legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: LinkedIn Corporation 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA. LinkedIn’s privacy policy: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>.

### d) Use of Bing Ads Conversion Tracking and remarketing

\- Bing Ads Conversion Tracking

Our website also uses the “Bing Ads Conversion Tracking” feature from Microsoft Corporation ("Microsoft") to measure the reach of ads. This is to determine how successful our individual advertising activities are on Bing and Yahoo. Our intention here is to develop and display advertising that is of interest to you and make our website more attractive. For this purpose, Microsoft’s UET tag (Universal Event Tracking tag) is integrated into our website. This JavaScript code enables Microsoft to use cookies to collect pseudonymous data about your visit and the use of our website (e.g. about the browser session and the website displayed) and to provide us with aggregated, non-personal statistics on this basis (e.g. how many visitors have reached a particular target page). This allows us to trace the actions that have taken place after an ad has been viewed or clicked on Bing or Yahoo.

\- Bing Ads remarketing

Our online offering also uses the “Bing Ads remarketing” feature. After visiting our website, this feature allows us to show you our ads when you continue to use the internet. Our intention here is to show you ads that are of interest to you. This is done by means of a cookie stored in your browser (see above for more information), which is used to record and evaluate your usage behavior. No personal information is transmitted to us about individual website visitors, and we can only specifically deploy ads to website custom audiences if the custom audience has reached a critical size. This makes it impossible for us to determine the individual identities of visitors.

There are various ways in which you can disable this tracking. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies, although this may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. You also can prevent Microsoft from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable Bing Ads Conversion Tracking and Remarketing. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. In addition, you can disable interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>) or e.g. part of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>); please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies. It is also possible to disable interest-based ads at <https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads>.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA. Microsoft’s privacy policy: <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement>.

### e) Use of Twitter Ads conversion tracking

Our website also uses the “Twitter Ads conversion tracking” feature from Twitter, Inc. (“Twitter”) to measure the reach of ads. This is to determine how successful our individual tweets and advertising activities are on Twitter. Our intention here is to develop and display advertising that is of interest to you and make our website more attractive. For this purpose, a conversion tag is integrated into our website. This JavaScript code enables Twitter to use cookies to collect pseudonymous data about your visit and the use of our website (e.g. about the browser session and the website displayed) and to provide us with aggregated, non-personal statistics on this basis (e.g. how many visitors have reached a particular target page). This allows us to trace the actions that have taken place after a tweet or an ad has been viewed or clicked on.

There are various ways in which you can disable this tracking. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies, although this may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. You also can prevent Twitter from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable Twitter Ads Conversion Tracking. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. In addition, you can disable interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>) or e.g. part of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>); please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Twitter’s privacy policy: <https://twitter.com/privacy>.

### f) Use of Webgains tracking

In addition, we use a plug-in of the international affiliate network Webgains, which is provided by ad pepper media GmbH (“Webgains”). This enables us to measure the success of our ads on partner sites brokered for us by Webgains. In this way we want to show you advertising that is of interest to you, make our website more attractive to you and achieve a fair calculation of advertising costs. For this purpose, a tracking code is integrated into our site. This code enables Webgains to collect pseudonymous data about your visit and the use of our online offer via cookies and make aggregated, non-personal statistics available to us on this basis, in particular about how many visitors of a certain partner site have ordered something from us after clicking on our advertisement.

There are various ways in which you can disable this tracking. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies, although this may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. You also can prevent Webgains from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnable Webgains tracking. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. In addition, you can disable interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>) or e.g. part of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>); please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Information from the third-party provider: Webgains Ltd, Third Floor, 21 Farringdon Road, London, EC1M 3HA, England. Webgains privacy policy: <http://www.webgains.com/public/en/privacy/>.

### g) Use of features by Spreadshirt’s Shop Partners

Our partners can also use a Facebook Pixel (see Section 2.7 b for a detailed explanation) in their Spreadshirt shops themselves, as a rule in order to be able to show you advertising on Facebook that is of interest to you after your visit to their shop, or in order to measure the reach of ads and in turn make their products more attractive. In this case, they determine the purposes and means of processing personal data. The name and contact details of our partners are stored in the legal information section of the respective shop.

### h) ShareASale

Our website uses tracking features from ShareASale, Inc. to identify the referrers of new Spreadshirt Shop Owners. This is to be able to credit referrers who introduce new people to our Spreadshop service. For this purpose, if you come to our website from a link containing ShareASale tracking features, a cookie is placed on your computer which enables ShareASale to attribute your signup to the referrer. This allows us to improve our strategies for promoting our Spreadshop service to potential users.

There are various ways in which you can disable this tracking. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies, although this may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. You also can prevent ShareASale from recording your data on this website by clicking here: DisableEnableShareASale conversion tracking. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. In addition, you can disable interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>) or e.g. part of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>); please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: ShareASale.com Inc., 15 W. Hubbard St. STE 500, Chicago IL 60654, USA. ShareASale Privacy policy: http://www.shareasale.com/PrivacyPolicy.pdf.

### i) Steel House Remarketing and Conversion Tracking

\- Steel House conversion tracking

Our website uses conversion tracking features from Steel House, Inc. to measure the reach of our ads. This is to determine how successful individual our advertising activities are. Our intention here is to develop and display advertising that is of interest to you and make our website more attractive. For this purpose, the Steel House Smarter Pixel is integrated into our website. This JavaScript code enables Steel House to use cookies to collect pseudonymous data about your visit and the use of our website (e.g. about the browser session and the website displayed) and to provide us with aggregated, non-personal statistics on this basis. This allows us to trace the actions that have taken place after an ad has been viewed or clicked on.

\- Steelhouse website retargeting

Our website also uses retargeting features from Steelhouse. After visiting our website, this feature makes it possible to show you our ads when you continue to use the internet. Our intention here is to show you ads that are of interest to you. This is done by means of a cookie stored in your browser (see above for more information), which is used to record and evaluate your usage behavior. No personal information is transmitted to us about individual website visitors. This makes it impossible for us to determine the individual identities of visitors.

There are various ways in which you can disable this tracking. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies, although this may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. You also can prevent Steel House from recording your data on this website by clicking here: Disable EnableSteelhouse conversion tracking and website retargeting. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. In addition, you can disable interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>) or e.g. part of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>); please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: Steel House, Inc., 3644 Eastham Drive Culver City, CA 9023, USA. Steelhouse privacy policy: https://steelhouse.com/privacy-policy/.

### j) Pinterest Tag

Our website uses the Pinterest Tag to track the actions people take on our website after seeing our Promoted Pins. We use this information to measure the reach and effectiveness of our ads on Pinterest and to create audiences to target with our Promoted Pins. This is done by means of a cookie stored in your browser (see above for more information), which is used to record and evaluate your usage behavior. No personal information is transmitted to us about individual website visitors. This makes it impossible for us to determine the individual identities of visitors.

There are various ways in which you can disable this tracking. You can adjust your browser settings to prevent the storage of cookies, although this may result in a restriction of the functionality of our website for you. You also can prevent Pinterest from recording your data on this website by clicking here: Disable EnablePinterest conversion tracking. This will place an opt-out cookie which prevents recording when you visit our website in future. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your device, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted; in this case, if you still wish to object then you must place the cookie again using the above button. The opt-out cookie is set per top-level domain, per browser and per device and only prevents the recording of data for this website. You can also follow the instructions here to prevent Pinterest from customizing your Pinterest boards based on your other online activity: https://help.pinterest.com/en/articles/personalization-and-data. In addition, you can disable interest-based ads from providers who are part of the “YourAdChoices” self-regulation initiative (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>) or e.g. part of the Network Advertising Initiative (<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>); please note that this setting will be erased if you erase your cookies.

The legal bases for the processing are your consent and our legitimate interests.

Third-party provider information: Pinterest Inc. at 651 Brannan Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. Pinterest privacy policy: https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy.

## 3\. What are my rights?

If you have given your consent to the processing of your data, you can revoke this consent with future effect at any time. This does not affect the lawfulness of processing carried out on the basis of the consent before you revoke your consent.

If we base the processing of your personal data on our legitimate interests, you are entitled to object to the processing. This is the case if the processing is not necessary in particular for the performance of a contract with you, which was described by us in each case with the description of the individual functions. When exercising such a right of objection, we ask that you explain the reasons why we should not process your personal data as carried out by us. In the event that your objection is justified, we will examine the situation and either stop or adjust the data processing or point out to you the compelling legitimate reasons on the basis of which we will continue processing.

However, you can of course object to the processing of your personal data for advertising or web analytics purposes at any time without giving reasons.

As described in the relevant sections, we sometimes use external service providers to process your data. These have been carefully selected and commissioned by us, are bound by our instructions and are regularly checked.

The personal data processed by us is generally erased or blocked as soon as the purpose of storage ceases to apply. Data may be stored for a longer period if this has been provided for by laws or other rules to which we as the controller are subject. The data will also be blocked or erased once a storage period prescribed by the aforementioned standards expires, unless there is a need for further storage of the data for the conclusion or performance of a contract.

Further processing operations may be required for contests and other promotional campaigns. In such cases we will inform you in the context of the respective promotional campaign.

## 4\. We Will Share Your Information with Third Parties in Specific Circumstances

### a) Legal Compliance and Safety

There are a few times when we must share your information either to protect our rights or to obey the law. We will share your personal information when we believe in good faith that:

  * a subpoena or warrant is duly issued, or we receive any other legitimate government agency request to produce information;
  * we need to share the information in order to enforce or protect our own rights, for example, to respond to and resolve third-party claims or complaints, or with respect to contracts with our users and third parties;
  * we need to address a security or technical issue within our website;
  * sharing the information is necessary to prevent harm to others or others’ property, especially in an emergency situation;

### b) Corporate Change in Control Events

If we sell all or part of our business, or make a sale or transfer of assets, or are otherwise involved in a similar event, we may transfer your information as part of that transaction.

## 5\. Is My Information Secure?

We use reasonable measures to secure our website and any private information you submit to us against loss, tampering, unauthorized access, and other malicious acts. For example, we use SSL connections when possible to protect your data while it is in transit (for example login data and customer orders). However, no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure, so we cannot completely guarantee the security of any data. You use our services at your own risk, and are responsible for taking reasonable measures to secure your password, information, and account.

## 6\. Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) Requests

Due to lack of technical standards across browsers, we do not respond to DNT signals.

## 7\. California Eraser Button Law

To the extent it is technically feasible and provided for and allowed by applicable law, you may email [info@spreadshirt.com](mailto:info@spreadshirt.com%20target=) anytime to ask for access to information held about you in order to have it corrected, disabled, or deleted, when possible.

California Eraser Button Law (Business and Professions Code §§ 22581): Note that removal or deletion of your information does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information posted on our website and service, or on the internet generally.

## 8\. Children’s Online Privacy Protection

Our website is not intended or directed at individuals under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect or keep any information of children under the age of 13. If we discover it, we will delete it as soon as possible.

## 9\. Effective Date and Changes

This policy is effective as of May 28, 2018. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be announced to you on the website and/or via email.

Thank you for reading this privacy policy in its entirety!
